Guide to the Jesuit Missionary Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Box and folder list, 1671 Nov 8-21
  - LOS MEDIOS, QUE PROPONE LA INSTRUCION [!] PARA FACILITAR LA CONDUCION [!] DEL GANADO DESDE SONORA AL INGENIO DE GUIMARAES ... (Box 2, Folder 50)
    [1749? n.p.]
    Detailed information concerning the many obstacles
    to transporting cattle. According to the docket,
    the author is the Provincial.
  - Mesa, Joseph de, d. 1749., 1749 Nov 29 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    LS
    [n.p.]
    1p., 31 cm.
    Signed by Mesa, Juan Honorado Ribera, and Joseph
    Joaquin de Rivera.
    Notification of attack by the Seris.
  - Miranda, Thomas, 1749 Nov 21-Dec 7 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    Populo and Nacomeri [Sonora, Mexico]
    3 ALS to Phelipe [i.e. Felipe] Segesser
    3p., 30-31 cm.
    Outrages of the Seris and necessity of putting
    them down.
  - Montt Vio, Ambrosio Juan, 1749 Dec 10 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    Real del Gavilan [Sonora, Mexico]
    ALS to Pheliph Zegeser [i.e. Felipe Segesser]
    Letter from a settler telling of the Indian raids
    and fears for his family.
  - Noriega, Francisco Xavier de, 1749 Dec 4 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    Real de San Joseph de Gracia [Arizona]
    ALS to Phelipe [i.e. Felipe] Segesser
    1p. 30 cm.
    Concerns five children in San Francisco, Arizona
    orphaned by Indian raids.
  - NOTICIAS DE LOS DISTURBIOS Y ALZAM[IEN]TO DE LOS SERIS, QUE VINIERON A CARPENA EN CARTA DE SU MUJER ESCRITA EL VICARIO DEL R[EA]L DE S[AN] JOSEPH CON F[EC]HA CINCO DE DIC[IEMB]RE DE 1749., 1749 Dec 5 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    Real de San Joseph
    2p. 21 cm.
    Concerns massacre by the Seri Indians at Aguape,
    with names of those killed.
  - Perera, Nicolas de, 1749 Nov 30 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Acontzi and Babiacora [i.e. Bavicora, 1749 Dec 10
    - Sonora, Mexico] 2 ALS to Phelippe [i.e. Felipe] Segesser 2p. 30.5 cm. Plans for a fiesta; danger of Seri attacks.
  - Rodriguez Gallardo, Joseph Raphael, 1749 Dec 3 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Ures and San Miguel de Horcasitas, 1749 Dec 4
    - Sonora Statements by Felipe Segesser, signed by Joseph Rodriguez Gallardo, Juan Joseph Montane, and Juan Honorado de Rivera. 4p. 30.5 cm. Danger of Seri attacks.
  - Rodriguez Gallardo, Joseph Raphael, 1749 Nov 27 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    San Miguel de Horcasitas, Sonora
    LS to Felipe Segesser
    2p. 30 cm.
    Concerns problems he has been investigating as
    Visitador.
  - Rojas, Carlos de, 1702-1773. (Box 2, Folder 59)
    [1749, Sonora, Mexico]
    Letter to the Visitador
    1p. 20.5 cm.
    The padres cannot take charge of provisioning
    troops.
  - Segesser, Felipe, 1689-1762., 1749 Dec 17 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    Pueblo de San Miguel de los Ures [Sonora, Mexico]
    AL to Joseph Raphael Rodriguez Gallardo
    2p. 31 cm.
    Arrival of squadron of soldiers to protect against
    the Seris.
  - Segesser, Felipe, 1689-1762., 1749 Dec 18 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    Ures [Sonora, Mexico]
    ALS to Juan Antonio Balthasar
    6p. 30.5 cm.
    Destruction by Seris and lack of protection
    against them. Refers to Joseph de Mesa, unaware
    that he had already been killed by the Seris.
  - Tagle de Bustamante, Francisco Antonio, 1749 Dec 14 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    San Miguel de Horcasitas [Sonora, Mexico]
    Concerns council of military and civil authorities
    on what should be done about the Seri Indians.
  - Toral, Joseph, d. ca. 1763., 1749 Dec 9 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    Guepaca
    LS to Provincial Andres Xavier Garcia
    19p., docketed 30.5 cm.
    Informing Mexico of Seri raids. "The Viceroy never
    knows what is going on here."
  - Toral, Joseph, d. ca. 1763., 1749 Dec 10 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    Banamichi [i.e. Benamichi, Sonora, Mexico]
    Dangers of Seri and Apache attacks.
  - Zavala, Pedro Joseph de, 1749 Oct 23 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    Pitiq [i.e. Pitiquito? Sonora, Mexico]
    LS to Phelipe [i.e. Felipe] Segesser
    6p. 31 cm.
    Vindication of his past conduct, and policies for
    his newly assumed post.